Make way, please.
同學 讓一讓
Sorry.
不好意思
I'm in a hurry for class.
我要著急上課啦
It's okay.
好了
Thank you.
謝謝
Chengcheng,
澄澄
your wound is deeper this time.
你這次傷口比較深
I've prescribed some more anti-inflammatory medicine.
我多開了一些消炎藥
Remember to take them regularly.
記得按時吃
Thank you.
謝謝
Senior, how do you know that
師兄 你怎麼知道
I don't eat cilantro?
我不吃香菜啊
Zhu Jiafa told me.
朱加法告訴我的
Senior Jiafa is so kind to me.
加法師兄對我真好
All right.
行吧
I saw you taking pictures with your family
今天早晨我在校門口
at the school gate this morning.
看見你跟你家人拍照
Why didn't you take a picture?
你為什麼不拍啊
That’s my father and my aunt.
那是我爸爸跟我阿姨
When the freshmen checked in,
新生報到的時候
I was the only one in the class
我是班裡面唯一一個
who checked in by myself.
自己來報到的
Many people took photos
當時好多好多好多人
at the school gate at that time.
在校門口拍照
But everyone was shooting
但大家都是
with the whole family.
全家一起拍的
I didn't really want to take pictures
我一個人
alone at that time.
當時就不是很想拍
After the school year started,
開學了以後吧
I thought it was a bit too touristy
又覺得在校門口拍照
to take photos at the school gate,
有點太遊客了
so I didn't take them either.
所以也沒拍
So
這麼想起來
it seems that I really haven’t
好像確實沒有正兒八經
taken any serious photos at the school gate.
在校門口拍過照
Where are we going?
去哪兒
Take you to take pictures.
帶你去拍照啊
Great.
挺好的
Good.
好
This one is beautiful.
這個好看
Thank you, Senior.
謝謝師兄
You’re welcome.
沒事
Let’s go.
走吧
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
同學 中秋快樂
Taste the mooncake.
嚐嚐月餅
Taste the mooncakes made by the school.
嚐嚐學校做的月餅
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
同學 中秋快樂
Try our school's homemade mooncakes.
嚐嚐學校自製的月餅
Thank you.
謝謝
I'll take it for him. Thank you.
我替他拿吧 謝謝啊
Okay, happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
好 中秋快樂
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
中秋快樂
Ham flavor,
雲腿味
egg yolk and lotus paste flavor.
蛋黃蓮蓉味
Which one do you like, Senior?
師兄 你喜歡吃哪個
I don't eat mooncakes. You eat.
我不吃月餅 你吃吧
I actually used to
我其實從前
love festivals.
特別喜歡過節
Because when it comes to the festival,
因為一到過節的時候
I had all kinds of reasons
我就有各種各樣的理由
to ask my parents
可以跟爸爸媽媽
for gifts and pocket money.
要禮物啊 要零用錢
But then they got divorced,
但是後來他們分開了
and I don't like the festivals anymore.
我就不喜歡過了
Because I didn't know
因為我都不知道
where to go.
該去哪兒
Don’t like.
不喜歡
When I was young, on the Mid-Autumn Festival,
小的時候一到中秋節
my family
我們全家就
went to the top of the mountain to enjoy the moon.
去山頂賞月
There was nothing really interesting.
其實也沒什麼好玩的
Our mountains are not high
我們那兒山又不高
and there were many people.
人又很多
It was full of barbecue stalls and small stalls.
全是燒烤攤和小地攤
So noisy.
吵吵鬧鬧的
It was the same every year.
每年皆是如此
So I got used to it.
也就習慣了
Then my parents got divorced,
後來爸媽分開了
and I didn't want to spend the Mid-Autumn Festival,
我就不想過中秋節
let alone eat mooncakes.
更不想吃月餅
Senior,
師兄
let me take you to a place.
我帶你去個地方吧
Where?
去哪兒
Here we are.
到了
It's so beautiful here.
這地兒真漂亮
How did you find this place?
你怎麼知道這兒的
Once I escaped from self-study at night
有一次我逃了晚自習
and wandered here.
閒逛到這兒的
Usually there are few people here.
平時這兒人也挺少的
Come with me.
跟我來
From here,
在這兒看
the whole city
整座城市
becomes especially small.
都變得特別渺小
Twinkle, twinkle.
一閃一閃的
Like a cartoon.
像動畫片一樣
I really like this place.
我真的很喜歡這兒
Unfortunately,
可惜了
there's no moon today.
今天沒有月亮
Senior, close your eyes.
師兄 你把眼睛閉上
Why?
幹嘛
Just close.
你閉上嘛
No.
不閉
Don't open .
不要偷睜開啊
Don’t be so nervous.
幹嘛呀 這麼緊張
Take it.
拿好
Don’t open your eyes.
不要睜開啊
Now,
我們現在
we're in a new world.
在一個嶄新的世界裡
Write all your worries
你把所有的煩惱
on this piece of paper.
都寫在這張紙上
Then put the paper
然後把紙
into a small box
放進一個小小的箱子裡
and lock it with a key.
用鑰匙鎖好
The paper airplane in your hand
手上的紙飛機
is the key to this box.
就是這個箱子的鑰匙
Now raise your arm,
現在抬起手臂
listen to my command,
聽我的口令
and then fly the paper plane out
一會兒用力地把紙飛機
with all your might.
飛出去
Then your worries
這樣你的煩惱
will float away
就會跟紙飛機一起
with the paper plane
飄向遠方
and never come back.
再也不會回來了
One,
一
two,
二
three.
三
Xiaomeng, cheers.
曉夢 來
Xiaomeng, I heard from your classmates that
曉夢 我聽你同學說
you are planning to go abroad after graduation.
你畢業之後準備出國
Have you decided where to go?
有想好去哪兒嗎
Not yet.
還沒有呢
Maybe
可能幾個學校
I'll apply to a few schools.
都會投一投吧
What's wrong, Senior?
怎麼了 師兄
Nothing.
沒什麼
I want to know which school you're going to.
我想知道你去哪個學校
We can go together in the future.
將來我們一起
Xiaomeng, in fact, I...
曉夢 其實我
Senior, I have to answer the phone first.
師兄 我先接個電話
Hello.
喂
What?
什麼
He withdrew the money again.
他又把錢取走了
I’ve told you many times that
我跟你說了多少次了
you must hide the money well,
錢你一定要藏好
and don't let him know the password.
密碼不能讓他知道
Why is it still like this?
怎麼還這樣
Hui doesn't have money for tuition, right?
小暉沒錢交學費是吧
How much are in short?
還差多少
Tell him
你跟他說
to be a little more aggressive.
讓他自己稍微爭點氣
He still needs to attend tuition classes.
補習班當然還是要上的
Whenever you eat, you swipe your phone.
一到吃飯就刷手機
Are there any rules at all?
到底還有沒有點規矩
When it comes to celebrity gossip,
一到講明星八卦
there's nothing you don't know.
就沒有你不知道的
When it comes to study and future planning,
一講到學習未來規劃
you just make light of it.
就輕描淡寫
I think
我看哪
you have a simple mind
你就是簡單的頭腦
but a complicated heart,
複雜的心
spending all your energy
把所有的精力
on things that aren't worth it.
都用在不值得的地方
You don't have the ability
重要的事情上
to think deeply
沒有一點
about the important things.
深度思考的能力
Come on, Dad.
行了吧 爸
Can you let me have a good meal?
能不能讓我好好吃個飯
Have some water.
喝點水
Brother,
哥哥
you've been waiting for a long time, right?
你等很久了吧
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival!
中秋快樂
It's okay.
沒事
I probably got it
這估計是剛剛
in the interest class.
興趣班上課的時候蹭的
Well, I'm going to go back.
那我先回去了
It's been three years,
都三年了
you still can't let it go?
你還過不去嗎
Chengcheng,
澄澄
thank you.
謝謝你
I'm happy today.
今天很開心
Unfortunately,
可惜了
there's still no moon.
還是沒有月亮
I also have a gift to you.
我也送你個禮物
Close your eyes.
你把眼睛閉上
Why?
幹嘛
No.
不閉
Just close.
閉一下
Don't peek.
別偷看啊
Okay.
好了
This is the moon I give you.
這個就是我送你的月亮
Although it's a bit rough.
雖然有點粗糙
No, I think it's cute.
沒呀 我覺得很可愛啊
Are you mocking me?
你是嘲諷我嗎
No, I'm not.
我沒有
It's really cute.
真挺可愛的
Let me project it into the sky for you.
我幫你把它投到天上去
The moon is coming out!
月亮出來了
Senior,
師兄
want some mooncakes?
你吃月餅嗎
Thank you.
謝謝
Is it good?
好吃嗎
Yes.
好吃
Are you teasing me as a dog?
你逗小狗呢
It's already late. why don’t sleep.
這都幾點了你還睡
Why are you...
你怎麼
What happened to your arm?
你的手怎麼了
I accidentally fell yesterday.
昨天不小心摔的
Your arm is injured,
手都摔壞了
why are you still so happy?
還這麼高興
Did you break your brain?
把腦子摔壞啦
Why are you back?
你怎麼回來了
Didn't you go out
你不是跟爸媽
with your parents?
出去玩了嗎
I had a fight with my parents,
我跟我爸媽吵架了
so I came back early.
就提前回來了
But
但是
even the atmosphere was so tense,
氣氛那麼緊張
I didn't forget
我都沒有忘記
to bring you the souvenirs.
把特產帶回來給你
How's that? Am I nice?
怎麼樣 夠意思吧
True sister.
真姐妹
At noon today,
今天中午
let’s eat in the Guojiao Canteen.
國交食堂吃小炒
It's on me.
我請客
Let's go now.
咱現在就走
Let's go.
走
Wait, I need to take a call.
你等會兒 接個電話
Hello? Senior Jiafa.
喂 加法師兄
Chengcheng, come over here.
澄澄 你快過來
Jianming has escaped from its cage.
建明跑出籠子了
Mr. Wang from the breeding room
飼養室的王老師
has gone home on vacation.
回家休假去了
Jianming hasn't seen him
現在建明連著好幾天
for a few days in a row,
見不著他
so it is anxious.
情緒有些焦慮啊
Okay, I'll come over and take a look.
好 那我過來看看
Okay, okay. Come over.
行行行 那你過來吧
Senior, well,
師兄 那個
is everyone in the lab?
實驗室大家都在呢嗎
Yes, we're all here.
在啊 都在呢
Is Senior Xiao also there?
小肖師兄也在呢嗎
Yuhe? Yuhe is here.
小肖 小肖在啊
It's useless even if he's here.
他在也沒用啊
He didn't feed Jianming.
他沒餵過建明啊
Okay, okay. Come on, come on.
好好好 那你來 來來
Waiting for you.
等你啊
Who is it?
誰啊
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Last time Jianming escaped,
上次建明跑出來
it was thanks to Chengcheng.
也多虧澄澄
She has experience.
她有經驗
Let her help out.
讓她來幫幫忙呀
No, I can handle it myself.
不用 我自己能處理
Really?
真的假的
Yes.
真的
I'll fix it for you right now.
我現在就給你解決
Come on, get out of the way.
來 讓開
Senior.
師兄
Senior Xiao.
小肖師兄
Senior Xiao was hit by Jianming.
小肖師兄被建明砸了
How is it?
怎麼樣了
He's still in there.
還在裡邊呢
Jianming hit him.
被建明砸了
I can't handle it.
我搞不定
Are you okay?
你沒事吧
Did you get scratched?
沒被撓吧
I'm fine.
沒事
Close the door.
關門
Oh, my God!
天哪
What are you doing? So noisy.
幹什麼呢 鬧鬧哄哄的
What are you doing?
幹什麼
Jianming.
建明
Look.
你看
Jianming is usually good.
建明平常挺乖的
It is splashing water.
潑水了
Hurry up!
快快快
Today Jianming is really...
建明今天真的是
Chengcheng, are you okay?
澄澄 你沒事吧
I'm not cold.
我不冷
Go back to the dormitory.
回宿舍吧
That monkey...
那猴
Go back.
回去吧
Go.
去吧
Well...
這
How...
怎麼
How about?
要不
Jianming is really...
這建明真是
There is a fly.
有隻蒼蠅
Should I go?
難道是我去嗎
Okay!
好
Is it just a monkey?
不就是隻猴嗎
Prof..
老師
Jianming, you can't do this.
建明 你不能這樣
Put it down.
放下
Jianming!
建明
Are you crazy?
你瘋啦
You... you're for real!
你 你來真格的
Prof. Du.
杜老師
Come on!
來呀
Fuck you!
去你的你
Prof. Du, are you okay?
老師 沒事吧
Hurry up!
快 快
Go get the keeper.
去找飼養員
Okay, let’s go.
好好好 快走
Don't all go.
別都去啊
Come back one.
回來一個
Mr. Wang from the breeding room
飼養室的王老師
has gone home on vacation.
回家休假去了
Jianming hasn't seen him
現在建明連著好幾天
for a few days in a row,
見不著他
so it is anxious.
情緒有些焦慮啊
Mr. Wang's clothes.
王老師的衣服
Mr. Wang's keys.
王老師的鑰匙
According to my observation,
據我觀察
Jianming is most sensitive
建明對氣味和聲音
to smells and sounds.
最為敏感
Play Jianming's
播放建明
favorite cartoon
最愛看的動畫片
to attract its attention.
吸引它的注意力
The clothes
衣服上
have Jianming’s familiar smell,
有建明熟悉的氣味
and the keys have its familiar sound.
鑰匙有建明熟悉的聲音
Just as I expected.
果然如我所料
It's done!
大功告成
You’re back.
回來了
Whose clothes are you wearing?
你這衣服誰的
What's going on?
什麼情況
This style looks familiar.
這個款式有點眼熟啊
Is it a man
是不是某位
named Xiao's?
肖姓男子的呀
I knew it.
我就知道
When I left,
我走的時候
you two were acting weird.
你們兩個就怪怪的
Is there something going on between you?
你們倆是不是有情況
What's going on with you and Xiao Yuhe?
你和肖宇河怎麼回事
Tell me. Tell me.
跟我說 跟我說
Why are your underwear transparent?
你這內衣怎麼透了
No wonder Xiao Yuhe
我說肖宇河
gave me his jacket.
怎麼要把外套給我穿呢
I'm too ashamed. I don't want to live anymore.
我丟死人了 我不活了
You mean that
你是說
Xiao Yuhe knew that
肖宇河知道
your clothes were wet,
你的衣服透了
so he took off his jacket
他就把自己的外套
and gave it to you?
脫下來然後給你穿
Is this the Xiao Yuhe
這是你之前
you told me about before?
跟我說的肖宇河嗎
He's changed his mind for you?
他為了你轉性了
What kind of idol drama is this?
這是什麼偶像劇的情節
This is so romantic.
這也太浪漫了吧
Do I believe in love again?
難道我又相信愛情了
That's great.
真是太好了
Look.
你看
Yes.
沒錯
The most important part
最重要的環節
is the new love skills
從劇本中學到的
learned from the script.
新戀愛技巧
The hero saves the beauty.
英雄救美
Hello, Senior Xiao.
小肖學長好
Let's go.
走啊
Are you okay?
你沒事吧
Yes, I just have a cold.
沒事 就是有點感冒
It is cold these days.
這兩天天氣降溫
Put on more clothes, don't catch a cold.
多穿點 別著涼了啊
Where's your jacket?
你外套呢
I left it in the lab.
落實驗室了
Do you need to go back and get it?
要 要回去取一下嗎
No, let's go.
不用 趕緊走吧
Let's go then.
那走
Let's go.
出發
Get on my beloved bike.
騎上我心愛的自行車
Is the power of love so great?
愛情的力量這麼偉大嗎
Su Chengcheng can get up by herself
蘇澄澄不用鬧鐘
without an alarm clock.
能自己起床了
Li Meizi,
李梅子
I...
我
I got his jacket dirty.
我把他的衣服弄髒了
Don’t worry, it's not obvious.
沒事 不明顯
Obvious, it’s obvious.
明顯 怎麼不明顯啊
Come down quickly.
你趕緊下來
Go with me to wash the clothes.
你陪我去洗個衣服吧
Kill me
“殺”了我吧
to cheer you up.
給你倆助助興
Meizi, Li Meizi.
梅子 李梅子
Li Meizi, Meizi, Li Meizi.
李梅子 梅子 李梅子
Meizi, Li Meizi, Li Meizi.
梅子 李梅子 李梅子
Li Meizi.
李梅子
Okay.
我下
Hurry up.
快點快點
Put more clothes in it.
你得多拿幾件
One piece won't get the machine running.
一件帶不動
That’s enough.
夠了 夠了
Why are they all white?
怎麼都是白的呀
I'm afraid that
我怕其他衣服
if the other clothes lose color,
萬一掉色的話
it will be stained.
再給它給染壞了
Disgusting.
我吐了
Show your love here.
秀恩愛都秀到這兒來了
Show off by washing clothes.
洗個衣服也能秀
The lab has a temporary meeting.
我實驗室臨時要開個會
I have to go there.
我得去一趟
When the laundry is done,
衣服洗完了
please help me take it out to dry.
你幫我拿出來晾一下唄
Okay.
好
Don't forget.
別忘了啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
I feel like
感覺這個
the left brain is used to listen to language
左腦好像是聽語言
and music.
和音樂啊
Really?
是嗎
Yes, the left ear...
對 左耳
Two people.
兩個人
Senior,
師兄 那個
I was going to return the clothes to you.
衣服我本來想還給你的
But it's a little bit dirty.
但是上面有一點髒了
Can I wash it
我能不能洗乾淨
and then bring it back to you?
拿給你啊
Okay.
行
What's wrong with you?
你怎麼了
Did you give me your jacket yesterday,
你是不是昨天
and you got cold?
把衣服給我自己凍著了
No, I'm allergic to pollen.
沒有 我花粉過敏
Isn't it autumn now?
現在不是秋天嗎
Chrysanthemum.
菊花
There are no chrysanthemums in our school.
我們學校沒有菊花啊
Osmanthus.
桂花
There is no osmanthus either.
桂花也沒有啊
Newly planted osmanthus? Where?
新種的 在哪兒
We're all here now.
大家都到得差不多了吧
Okay.
行
Before we start,
那在正式開始之前
let me tell you
我先跟大家
one little thing.
說一件小事啊
Last week, I went to Shanghai with your senior sister
上週呢 我跟你們師姐
to attend a meeting.
去上海蔘加了一個交流
I accidentally mentioned
無意間呢
the love experiment
就提到了我們實驗室
in our lab before.
之前的那個喜歡實驗
The experiment
就是小肖和蘇澄澄同學
Yuhe and Su Chengcheng did.
做的那個實驗
Many people are interested in it,
有不少人感興趣
and hope that
希望我們這個實驗啊
our experiment
可以繼續地往下
can be extended further.
延伸一下
Because
因為就現有的
in terms of the current technology,
科技水平而言
it is indeed impossible to define liking.
喜歡的確是無法界定的
But it doesn't prevent us
但是不妨礙
from observing it
我們從不同的角度
from different angles.
對它進行觀測
I have found a small direction.
我找了一個小小的方向
To study the difference in brain activity
研究男女兩性
between men and women
在加工浪漫信息時
when processing romantic information.
腦區活動的差異
In this way,
這樣呢 可以給我們
we can accumulate some data,
積累一些數據
which is also
對我們的研究
helpful for our research.
也很有幫助
At the weekly sharing meeting,
這樣每週的分享會上
you can share
可以把觀測到的結果
your observations
拿出來
with us.
跟大家分享一下
It's time to start dating at public expense again,
又要開始公費談戀愛了
and abuse singles openly
還是打著學術的幌子
under the guise of academics.
光明正大地虐狗
Actually,
其實啊
the most important part
這個實驗的
is to study the similarities and differences
是研究異性差異
in the activation of different parts of the brain
在加工浪漫信息時
during the processing of romantic information by the opposite sex.
啟用腦區各部的異同
It doesn't have much to do
這個跟喜不喜歡啊
with liking.
其實也沒有太大的關係
If you are interested,
大家如果感興趣的話
just participate in the experiment.
就一起參加唄
Look,
看看 看看
our dean still cares about
咱們院長還是很關愛
us singles .
我們這些單身狗的
Okay, you all go back
行 這樣大家都回去
and get ready.
準備一下
You can divide up into groups, okay?
可以分分組 好吧
Okay.
好
Okay, let's get back to the subject.
行 我們言歸正傳
Let's discuss
咱們來先討論一下
some key points
上個星期
of our academic research
我們這個學術研究的
last week.
一些重點啊
Students, you're all so serious.
同學們 都這麼認真啊
Hello, Prof. Du.
杜老師好
Go on with your work.
忙你們的 忙你們的
Nothing, I'm here
沒事 我過來看看
to check some data
我們之前工作室的
from our previous studio.
幾個數據
Senior Xiao
小肖師兄
has been using this machine.
之前一直用這台機子
Okay, go on with your work.
行 忙吧
Okay.
好
Go on with your work.
你們先忙啊
Xiao,
肖
Prof. Du asks you to go to the office.
杜老師讓你去趟辦公室
Are you still
你是不是
developing Musk
還在一個人
by yourself in secret?
偷偷地開發馬斯克
Why are you doing this?
你為什麼要這麼做
Do you still want to
難道你還想繼續參加
participate in this year's competition?
今年的比賽啊
Yes.
是
Nonsense!
是什麼
You're completely fooling around!
你這完全是在瞎胡鬧
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河同學
I'm not stopping you from pursuing your dream.
我不是攔著你追求理想
I hope you
我希望你
realize your dreams.
實現自己的夢想
I also hope that
我也希望有一天
one day you will become a valuable
你成為一個有價值
and successful
並且是一個有成就的
researcher.
科研人員
But have you thought about
但是你有沒有想過呀
what you will face
你現在如果去參加
if you go to
這個比賽
this competition now?
你將會面臨什麼
Don't forget
你到什麼時候
the incident
你都不要忘了
happened three years ago,
三年前的那件事情
which had a very bad impact.
鬧得影響非常地惡劣
If you go to the competition
如果這個時候
at this time,
你去參加比賽
there are many difficulties
有很多困難
that you can't even imagine.
是你根本想都想不到的
Even if you think about it,
即使你想到了
you can not solve it.
你也解決不了
Senior,
師兄
what’s going on?
到底是怎麼回事
Several years ago,
前些年
Senior Xiao
小肖師兄參加了一個
took part in a competition.
什麼比賽
The robot he made
做的那個機器人
lost control on the spot
當場就失控了
and hurt people.
害人受了傷
Crucially, he clashed
關鍵他還跟工作人員
with the staff.
起了衝突
Then things got worse and worse.
後來動靜鬧得越來越大
He even went abroad to study
他還專門出國
for a few years.
讀了幾年書
He just went back to school this year.
這不 今年才回學校
Why did the robot go out of control?
機器人為什麼會失控啊
The robot went out of control...
機器人失控
I don't know exactly what happened.
具體情況我也不太清楚
I heard it from someone else.
我是聽別人說的
I really don't know.
真不清楚
Meizi, what's wrong?
梅子 怎麼了
What about the other clothes? Are they all there?
那別的衣服呢 都在嗎
Only that one is gone.
就那件沒有了
How could this happen?
那怎麼會這樣呢
Don't worry, don't worry.
你別急你別急
I'm going back to the dorm.
我現在回宿舍
Don't worry.
別急啊
Okay, okay, okay.
好好好
What happened?
怎麼了
Just now I deliberately set a time
剛才我特意定了時間
to come to pick it up.
過來取的
When I came over,
然後等我過來的時候
your clothes
你的衣服
had all been put aside.
就已經全放在一邊了
And Xiao Yuhe's jacket
然後肖宇河的那件
was gone.
沒有了
Don’t worry, let’s find it.
沒事 我們再找找
I've told you everything.
這該說的也都跟你說了
In fact,
其實啊
I quite understand your insistence.
我挺理解你這種堅持的
Researchers
搞科研的人嘛
should have the spirit of
就應該有這股子
not being afraid to lose.
不怕輸的精神
But this is
但是現在具體情況
the situation now.
就放在這兒
I think,
我考慮
for one thing,
一方面啊
the technical difficulty of Musk
是這馬斯克的技術
is too much
難度太大了
for you to deal with alone.
你一個人很難應付
For another thing,
再一個
I am also very worried about it.
也是我非常擔心的
If you participate in this competition,
如果說你這次參加比賽
if someone
萬一有那種
with ulterior motives
別有用心的人
digs up what happened back then,
把當年的事情挖出來
it will be harmful to you
那對你和對這個實驗室
and to our lab.
那都是有傷害的
Right?
對吧
Given your character,
以你的性格
even if I ask you
我現在就說
to give up now,
你放棄
you won't do it.
你也不幹
Well,
你這樣
let's stop for a while.
那咱們暫時停一停
You think about it.
你也考慮考慮
I'll think about it too.
我也考慮考慮
When we figure it out,
等想明白了
then let’s talk about it
咱們找個時間
sometime,
再聊一聊
and see what we can do about it.
看這個事到底怎麼辦
But,
但是
until we come to a conclusion,
在沒有一個結論之前
I want you
我希望你
to put down
把機械實驗室的門卡
the door card of the mechanical lab.
放下
It's okay.
沒事
Where's Su Chengcheng?
蘇澄澄呢
She's going to...
她去
Su Chengcheng has gone back to the dorm.
蘇澄澄回宿舍了
Senior Xiao,
肖學長
what's wrong
你說這蘇澄澄
with  Su Chengcheng?
怎麼回事啊
She's not active in her studies,
學習學習不積極
but she's lazier than anyone else.
那偷懶跑得比誰都快
Are you done?
說完了嗎
Yes.
說完了
Go on with your work.
忙啊
Whose jacket is this?
這是誰的衣服呀
Here it is.
在這兒呢